A Guide to the Social Movements Collection, ca. 1959-1989, 2000, and n.d.
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Social Movements Collection ca. 1959-1989, 2000, and n.d.
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
9430-f
Ca. 5,500 items (20 Hollinger boxes, 8.5 linear feet).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the University of Virginia Library by John Shepherd for the estate of Charles P. Finn, Charlottesville, Virginia, on April 3, 1989.
Biographical/Historical Information
Charles Patrick Finn was born in Germantown, Pennsylvania in 1947. Finn began working for the University of Virginia Library system in 1969 in the Serials section of the Cataloging Department, and remained at Alderman Library until his death in 1988. Finn was one of the founders of the Library's Committee for a Social Movements Collection, which acquired items from social movement groups including newsletters, posters, buttons, mailings, clippings, and stickers throughout the 1960s, 1970s, and 1980s. Finn was an anarchist and was active in politics and the anti-war movement throughout his life. In his own words, Charlie described collecting social movements materials: "My hobby can better be described as an avocation: analysis of the Indochina War and the problems and struggles that conflict has drawn attention to. For me, Vietnam has remained an obsession so that radical political action to end that war and change society takes precedence over more 'conventional' hobbies."
Scope and Content
This collection consists of papers concerning various radical political organizations and social action groups in the United States, including the University of Virginia, chiefly collected by Charles Finn, ca. 1959-1989, 2000, and undated, ca. 5,500 items (20 Hollinger boxes, 8.5 linear feet). Social action groups included in the collection span both radical left and right wing groups including Students for a Democratic Society, Southern Student Organizing Committee, The Weather Underground, Freedom From Religion Foundation, National Organization for Women, Jerry Falwell, The Moral Majority, National Knights of the Ku Klux Klan, and a diversity of other environmental, religious, social and political organizations. The majority of the items are dated between 1970 and 1988. Related printed material has been transferred to Rare Books and catalogued separately. There is a large section of material on various organizations active at the University of Virginia, and specifically there is a section of material concerning the May 1970 Strike (Box 16) including event schedules, correspondence, and a student thesis written about the strike.
Arrangement
These papers have been organized into three series: Series I: Topical Files (Boxes 1-18); Series II: Memorabilia (Box 19); and Series III: Personal Papers of Charlie Finn (Box 20). The Topical Files have been organized by social movement group at the folder level, and chronologically within folders. The Memorabilia files include buttons, stickers, and other accessories. They have been organized by type of memorabilia and social movement group. The Personal Papers of Charlie Finn series includes correspondence, papers from the University of Virginia Library system, and miscellaneous written notes.
Separated Material
Related printed material has been transferred to Rare Books and cataloged separately. Each item contains the note "SPECIAL COLLECTIONS: Transferred from the Social Movements Collection, MSS 9430" and can be found in the online catalog by a keyword search for "Social Movements Collection."
Contents List
- Series I: Topical Files
  - Abalone Alliance 1981 (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Abu Ein Defense Committee n.d. (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Accuracy In Media (AIM) 1977, n.d. (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Action for Forgotten Women 1975 (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Action for Women in Chile 1980 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Action on Smoking and Health (ASH) n.d. (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Ad Hoc Coalition for Euromissile Actions n.d. (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Ad Hoc Committee for a July 2 Emergency Mobilization 1983 (Box-folder 1:8)
  - Ad Hoc Committee to Support Irish Political Prisoners 1980-1981, n.d. (Box-folder 1:9)
  - The Africa Fund 1976-1985, n.d. (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Agape Foundation 1980-1982 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - A. J. Muste Memorial Institute 1981 (Box-folder 1:12)
  - Albania Report 1980 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - All-Peoples Congress 1981 (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Amalgamated Clothing and Textiles Workers Union [1978] (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Amalgamated Transit Union, AFL-CIO n.d. (Box-folder 1:16)
  - Ambulances for Nicaragua n.d. (Box-folder 1:17)
  - America-Israel Council for Israeli-Palestinian Peace 1982-1988 (Box-folder 1:18)
  - America's Corporate Conscience Awards 1988 (Box-folder 1:19)
  - American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee 1981-1989 (Box-folder 1:20)
  - American Atheist Press 1985 (Box-folder 1:21)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU) 1982-1988 (Box-folder 1:22)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU): Central Virginia Chapter, Charlottesville, Virginia 1983 (Box-folder 1:23)
  - The American Committee for Justice in the Middle East 1970 (Box-folder 1:24)
  - American Committee on Africa 1979-1981, n.d. (Box-folder 1:25)
  - The American Council n.d. (Box-folder 1:26)
  - American Council of Christian Laymen n.d. (Box-folder 1:27)
  - American Council of Life Insurance 1983 (Box-folder 1:28)
  - The American Democratic Political Action Committee 1984 (Box-folder 1:29)
  - American Family Association n.d. (Box-folder 1:30)
  - American Federation of Labor (AFL-CIO) 1980 (Box-folder 1:31)
  - AFL-CIO Solidarity Day 1981 (Box-folder 1:32)
  - American Friends Service Committee 1972-1988, n.d. (Box-folder 1:33)
  - American-Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition, Inc. 1982-1984, n.d. (Box-folder 1:34)
  - American Opinion n.d. (Box-folder 1:35)
  - The American Palestine Committee n.d. (Box-folder 1:36)
  - The American Party n.d. (Box-folder 1:37)
  - Americans for Democratic Action n.d. (Box-folder 1:38)
  - Americans for Religious Liberty n.d. (Box-folder 1:39)
  - Amnesty International: Group 157: Charlottesville, Virginia 1975-1988, n.d. (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Another Mother for Peace 1971 (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith n.d. (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Anti-War Union n.d. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Appeal for Reconciliation 1976, n.d. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Arab American Community of Richmond n.d. (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Arab American Institute 1985 (Box-folder 2:7)
  - Arab Information Center, League of Arab States 1971-1973 (Box-folder 2:8)
  - Arabs and Jews for a Democratic Palestine n.d. (Box-folder 2:9)
  - Asbury United Methodist Church, Brandywine Peace Community 1982-1988, n.d. (Box-folder 2:10)
  - Asia Information Group 1971 (Box-folder 2:11)
  - Asian Information Office (AIO) n.d. (Box-folder 2:12)
  - Assassination Information Bureau 1977 (Box-folder 2:13)
  - Assata Shakur Defense Committee 1976 (Box-folder 2:14)
  - Assembly to Save the Peace Agreement 1976 (Box-folder 2:15)
  - Association of Women of El Salvador n.d. (Box-folder 2:16)
  - Atlantans Concerned for El Salvador n.d. (Box-folder 2:17)
  - Attorney General's Office of the United States 1988 (Box-folder 2:18)
  - Baltimore Regional Joint Board ACWA n.d. (Box-folder 2:19)
  - Billy Graham Evangelistic Association 1984 (Box-folder 2:20)
  - Black Liberation Press n.d. (Box-folder 2:21)
  - The Black Mountain Press 1968 (Box-folder 2:22)
  - Blue Angel, Inc. 1981 (Box-folder 2:23)
  - Bob Dole n.d. (Box-folder 2:24)
  - Bob Packwood: United States Senator for Oregon 1987-1989 (Box-folder 2:25)
  - Bobby Banks 1980-1982 (Box-folder 2:26)
  - The Bolshevik League of the United States n.d. (Box-folder 2:27)
  - Boston Committee for Medical Aid to El Salvador n.d. (Box-folder 2:28)
  - Boston Eight 1969 (Box-folder 2:29)
  - Brethren Press 1987 (Box-folder 2:30)
  - Bright Morning Star 1980 (Box-folder 2:31)
  - Brooklyn Ecumenical Cooperatives (BEC) 1985 (Box-folder 2:32)
  - Bruce Beyer Defense Committee n.d. (Box-folder 2:33)
  - The Bullet: Mary Washington College 1967 (Box-folder 2:34)
  - California Newsreel 1980, n.d. (Box-folder 2:35)
  - California State University, Fullerton: Freedom Center 1975, n.d. (Box-folder 2:36)
  - The Call to Resist, A New Call to Resist n.d. (Box-folder 2:37)
  - Calvert Social Investment Fund 1985-1988 (Box-folder 2:38)
  - Calvin Memorial Presbyterian Church Legal Defense Fund: David Rice and Ed Poindexter n.d. (Box-folder 2:39)
  - Camden 28 Defense Committee n.d. (Box-folder 2:40)
  - Cameron Bishop Defense 1975, n.d. (Box-folder 2:41)
  - Campaign for a Democratic Foreign Policy n.d. (Box-folder 2:42)
  - Campaign for Peace and Democracy East and West 1988, n.d. (Box-folder 2:43)
  - Campaign for Peace and Justice in Central America n.d. (Box-folder 2:44)
  - Campaign for Political Rights n.d. (Box-folder 2:45)
  - Campaign to Oppose Bank Loans to South Africa n.d. (Box-folder 2:46)
  - Campaign to Stop Government Spying 1977 (Box-folder 2:47)
  - Canadian Aid for Vietnam Civilians 1970-1971, n.d. (Box-folder 2:48)
  - Candlelight March for Soviet Jewry: University of Virginia 1986-1987 (Box-folder 2:49)
  - The Capp Street Foundation 1988 (Box-folder 2:50)
  - The Carcinogen Information Program, Inc. 1978-1982 (Box-folder 2:51)
  - Caribbean Basin Information Project n.d. (Box-folder 2:52)
  - Carolina Interfaith Taskforce on Central America n.d. (Box-folder 2:53)
  - Casa El Salvador "Farabundo Marti" n.d. (Box-folder 2:54)
  - Catholic Peace Fellowship n.d. (Box-folder 2:55)
  - The Catholic Worker n.d. (Box-folder 2:56)
  - Catholics for a Free Choice n.d. (Box-folder 2:57)
  - Caucus on Peace and War n.d. (Box-folder 2:58)
  - Celebrate Life n.d. (Box-folder 2:59)
  - Center for Constitutional Rights 1985, n.d. (Box-folder 2:60)
  - Center for Economic Democracy 1983 (Box-folder 2:61)
  - Center for International Policy 1986 (Box-folder 2:62)
  - Center for National Security Studies n.d. (Box-folder 2:63)
  - Center for Science in the Public Interest n.d. (Box-folder 2:64)
  - Center for the Study of the Americas n.d. (Box-folder 2:65)
  - Center for Third World Organizing 1986-1987 (Box-folder 2:66)
  - Center on Law and Pacifism 1979 (Box-folder 2:67)
  - Central America Health Rights Network 1986 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - Central America Media Education Project n.d. (Box-folder 3:2)
  - Central American Refugee Center 1987 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - Central Committee for Conscientious Objectors (CCCO): An Agency for Military and Draft Counseling 1979-1986, n.d. (Box-folder 3:4)
  - Central Labor Council n.d. (Box-folder 3:5)
  - Central Massachusetts Safe Energy Project, Inc. 1981 (Box-folder 3:6)
  - The Central Virginia Citizens Party 1980-1982, n.d. (Box-folder 3:7)
  - Central Virginia Nuclear Freeze Campaign (CVNFC): Charlottesville, Virginia 1982-1983, n.d. (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Chapel Hill Peace Center 1976 (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Charlottesville Activists' Coalition 1980-1981, n.d. (Box-folder 3:10)
  - Charlottesville-Albemarle Council on Human Relations 1968 (Box-folder 3:11)
  - Charlottesville-Albemarle Peace Center 1973 (Box-folder 3:12)
  - Charlottesville and Albemarle County Chamber of Commerce n.d. (Box-folder 3:13)
  - Charlottesville Citizens for Peace in Vietnam 1968 (Box-folder 3:14)
  - Charlottesville Democrats for City Council: Alvin Edwards, Tom Vanderver, Bitsy Waters 1988 (Box-folder 3:15)
  - Charlottesville Draft Action n.d. (Box-folder 3:16)
  - Charlottesville Draft Opposition n.d. (Box-folder 3:17)
  - Charlottesville Draft Resistance n.d. (Box-folder 3:18)
  - Charlottesville [Guerilla] Theater 1972 (Box-folder 3:19)
  - Charlottesville Latin America Solidarity Committee (CLASC) 1981-2000, n.d. (Box-folder 3:20)
  - Charlottesville Latin America Support Center (CLASC) 1984-1988, n.d. (Box-folder 3:21)
  - Charlottesville Nestle Boycott Organization n.d. (Box-folder 3:22)
  - Charlottesville Peace Action Center (C-PAC) 1980 (Box-folder 3:23)
  - Charlottesville Peace Center 1986-1987, n.d. (Box-folder 3:24)
  - Charlottesville Resistance 1970-1978, n.d. (Box-folder 3:25)
  - Charlottesville Social Development Commission 1983 (Box-folder 3:26)
  - Charlottesville Socialist Feminist Alliance n.d. (Box-folder 3:27)
  - Charlottesville YIP: Youth International Party n.d. (Box-folder 3:28)
  - Chicago Defense Committee 1970 (Box-folder 3:29)
  - Chicago Religious Task Force on Central America 1984 (Box-folder 3:30)
  - Christian Book Club of America n.d. (Box-folder 3:31)
  - Christian Defense League n.d. (Box-folder 3:32)
  - The Christic Institute 1981-1988, n.d. (Box-folder 3:33)
  - Christopher News Notes 1984 (Box-folder 3:34)
  - Church of the Brethren 1973-1982 (Box-folder 3:35)
  - Church Women United in Virginia: Charlottesville, Virginia n.d. (Box-folder 3:36)
  - Church World Service 1978 (Box-folder 3:37)
  - Christians for Israel: Jerry Falwell n.d. (Box-folder 3:38)
  - Citizen Soldier 1984-1988, n.d. (Box-folder 3:39)
  - Citizens' Action for Safe Energy, Inc. 1982 (Box-folder 3:40)
  - Citizens Against Video Victimization 1983, n.d. (Box-folder 3:41)
  - Citizen's Clearinghouse for Hazardous Wastes, Inc. 1984-1988, n.d. (Box-folder 3:42)
  - Citizens' Commission to Investigate the FBI n.d. (Box-folder 3:43)
  - Citizens Party: National 1980-1982, n.d. (Box-folder 3:44)
  - Civil Liberties Legal Defense Fund, Inc. 1971 (Box-folder 3:45)
  - Clamshell Alliance 1988-1989, n.d. (Box-folder 4:1)
  - Clarity Press n.d. (Box-folder 4:2)
  - Claudine Schneider for United States Senate 1986 (Box-folder 4:3)
  - Clean Up Television: Jerry Falwell n.d. (Box-folder 4:4)
  - Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC) 1976-1979, n.d. (Box-folder 4:5)
  - Coalition n.d. (Box-folder 4:6)
  - Coalition for a New Foreign and Military Policy 1976-1986, n.d. (Box-folder 4:7)
  - Coalition for a Non-Nuclear World 1980, n.d. (Box-folder 4:8)
  - Coalition for a People's Alternative n.d. (Box-folder 4:9)
  - Coalition for a People's Alternative in 1980 1980 (Box-folder 4:10)
  - Coalition for Direct Action at Seabrook 1979-1980, n.d. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Coalition to End Grand Jury Abuse 1980, n.d. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Coalition to Stop Funding the War, Ad Hoc Coalition for a New Foreign Policy 1975-1976, n.d. (Box-folder 4:13)
  - Columbia House n.d. (Box-folder 4:14)
  - Comité de Apoyo Pro-Alfabetización (CAPA): The Literacy Support Committee n.d. (Box-folder 4:15)
  - Commission on United States-Central American Relations 1985, n.d. (Box-folder 4:16)
  - Committee Against Government Waste n.d. (Box-folder 4:17)
  - Committee Against Psychiatric Assault n.d. (Box-folder 4:18)
  - Committee Against Registration and the Draft (CARD) 1980-1987, n.d. (Box-folder 4:19)
  - Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy (SANE), Citizens Organization for a Sane World 1973-1986, n.d. (Box-folder 4:20)
  - Committee for a Social Movements Collection n.d. (Box-folder 4:21)
  - Committee for Abortion Rights and Against Sterilization Abuse n.d. (Box-folder 4:22)
  - Committee for Human Rights and Democracy in Turkey n.d. (Box-folder 4:23)
  - Committee for Palestine Solidarity n.d. (Box-folder 4:24)
  - Committee for Puerto Rican Decolonization n.d. (Box-folder 4:25)
  - Committee for Responsible Genetics n.d. (Box-folder 4:26)
  - Committee for the Freedom of the Puerto Rican Nationalist Prisoners 1975, n.d. (Box-folder 4:27)
  - The Committee for the Suit Against Government Misconduct 1968-1981, n.d. (Box-folder 4:28)
  - Committee in Solidarity with the People of El Salvador (CISPES) 1980-1984, n.d. (Box-folder 4:29)
  - Committee in Solidarity with the People of Latin America and the Caribbean (CISPLAC) 1982 (Box-folder 4:30)
  - Committee of Concerned Asian Scholars n.d. (Box-folder 4:31)
  - Committee of Returned Volunteers n.d. (Box-folder 4:32)
  - The Committee on Mission Responsibility through Investment 1986-1987, n.d. (Box-folder 4:33)
  - Committee to Defend Carlos Feliciano 1974 (Box-folder 4:34)
  - Committee to Defend Imani (Johnny Harris) and Stop the Death Penalty 1979-1983, n.d. (Box-folder 4:35)
  - Committee to Defend NASSCO Workers 1981, n.d. (Box-folder 4:36)
  - Committee to Defend the Panthers n.d. (Box-folder 4:37)
  - Committee to Honor New Afrikan Freedom Fighters n.d. (Box-folder 4:38)
  - Committee to Save the Iranian 14 n.d. (Box-folder 4:39)
  - Committee to Support Irish Political Prisoners 1983 (Box-folder 4:40)
  - Committee to Support Middle East Liberation n.d. (Box-folder 4:41)
  - Common Cause 1987-1988, n.d. (Box-folder 4:42)
  - Common Sense Foundation n.d. (Box-folder 4:43)
  - Communist Workers Part Five Memorial and Legal Defense Fund 1979 (Box-folder 4:44)
  - Community for Creative Non-Violence 1981-1982, n.d. (Box-folder 4:45)
  - Concerned Jewish Citizens n.d. (Box-folder 4:46)
  - Congressional Agenda: 80's 1984-1986, n.d. (Box-folder 4:47)
  - Congressional Directory 1981 (Box-folder 4:48)
  - Connections 1981 (Box-folder 4:49)
  - Conscience and Military Tax Campaign n.d. (Box-folder 4:50)
  - Concerned Citizens of Louisa County, Mineral, Virginia n.d. (Box-folder 4:51)
  - Conference on the International Situation, War, Revolution, and the Internationalist Tasks of the American People 1976, n.d. (Box-folder 4:52)
  - Conscience and Military Tax Campaign n.d. (Box-folder 4:53)
  - Garden Gourmet Vegetarian Restaurant n.d. (Box-folder 4:54)
  - Conservatives Against Liberal Legislation 1983 (Box-folder 4:55)
  - The Conspiracy 1969, n.d. (Box-folder 4:56)
  - The Conspiracy to Save Lives 1971 (Box-folder 4:57)
  - Constitution Federal Committee (PAC) n.d. (Box-folder 4:58)
  - Contingent in Solidarity with the Vietnamese People 1967, n.d. (Box-folder 4:59)
  - Coral Ridge Ministries 1985 (Box-folder 4:60)
  - Corporation Court: Law Orders: Charlottesville, Virginia 1970-1971 (Box-folder 5:1)
  - Corpus Christi n.d. (Box-folder 5:2)
  - Council for a Livable World 1985-1986 (Box-folder 5:3)
  - Council for a Livable World Education Fund 1985-1986 (Box-folder 5:4)
  - Council on Economic Priorities 1988 (Box-folder 5:5)
  - Country Conscience 1986 (Box-folder 5:6)
  - Creative Roots, Inc., Publishers n.d. (Box-folder 5:7)
  - Cultural Survival, Inc. 1986 (Box-folder 5:8)
  - The Daily Death Toll n.d. (Box-folder 5:9)
  - Dalkon Shield Information Nework, Inc.: National Women's Health Network (NWHN) 1987, n.d. (Box-folder 5:10)
  - David Fine Freedom Committee n.d. (Box-folder 5:11)
  - David Toscano for Congress: Citizen's Party, Charlottesville, Virginia n.d. (Box-folder 5:12)
  - The Day 1986 (Box-folder 5:13)
  - The Defense Committee 1971, n.d. (Box-folder 5:14)
  - The Democratic Party n.d. (Box-folder 5:15)
  - The Democratic Socialists of America n.d. (Box-folder 5:16)
  - Dissent! n.d. (Box-folder 5:17)
  - Do It Now Foundation 1973-1977 (Box-folder 5:18)
  - Dollars and Sense 1987 (Box-folder 5:19)
  - Donal Day for House of Delegates 24th District n.d. (Box-folder 5:20)
  - Draft Action 1982-1984 (Box-folder 5:21)
  - Dukakis for President n.d. (Box-folder 5:22)
  - Eagle Forum 1978 (Box-folder 5:23)
  - East Timor Human Rights Committee 1981, n.d. (Box-folder 5:24)
  - East Timor Information and Research Project 1976 (Box-folder 5:25)
  - Eastern Kentucky Welfare Rights Organization (EKWRO) 1972 (Box-folder 5:26)
  - Ecumenical Program for Interamerican Communication and Action n.d. (Box-folder 5:27)
  - Educators for Social Responsibility n.d. (Box-folder 5:28)
  - Edythe Harrison for United States Senate 1984 (Box-folder 5:29)
  - Effective Learning Systems, Inc. n.d. (Box-folder 5:30)
  - El Greco of Toledo n.d. (Box-folder 5:31)
  - El Salvador Alert! 1981 (Box-folder 5:32)
  - Elias Ayoub Defense Committee 1979-1981, n.d. (Box-folder 5:33)
  - Emergency Committee to Defend Palestinian Mayors 1980 (Box-folder 5:34)
  - EnAct/PAC n.d. (Box-folder 5:35)
  - Energy Investment Research, Inc. 1984-1985 (Box-folder 5:36)
  - Energy Systems Research Group, Inc. 1984 (Box-folder 5:37)
  - Environmental Action 1983-1984, n.d. (Box-folder 5:38)
  - Environmental Defense Fund 1982-1988 (Box-folder 5:39)
  - Equal Time 1986, n.d. (Box-folder 5:40)
  - Eritrean Relief Committee 1977-1980 (Box-folder 5:41)
  - The Experimental University n.d. (Box-folder 5:42)
  - Extra! n.d. (Box-folder 5:43)
  - FAIR: Fairness and Accuracy In Reporting 1987, n.d. (Box-folder 5:44)
  - Fair Play for Cuba Committee n.d. (Box-folder 5:45)
  - Farabundo Marti National Liberation Front 1988 (Box-folder 5:46)
  - Farm Labor Organizing Committee 1983-1986, n.d. (Box-folder 5:47)
  - Federal Register 1983 (Box-folder 5:48)
  - Federation of Alternative Libraries 1979 (Box-folder 5:49)
  - The Fellowship of Reconciliation 1976-1983 (Box-folder 5:50)
  - Fifth Avenue Marijuana Parade Coalition n.d. (Box-folder 5:51)
  - Fifth District Voters League PAC: Dillwyn, Virginia 1981 (Box-folder 5:52)
  - First Aid 1971 (Box-folder 5:53)
  - The Fortune Society n.d. (Box-folder 5:54)
  - Foundation for Middle East Peace n.d. (Box-folder 5:55)
  - Foundation for the Study of Independent Social Ideas, Inc. 1981 (Box-folder 5:56)
  - Frank Shuford Defense Committee 1979 (Box-folder 5:57)
  - Franklin's Insight n.d. (Box-folder 5:58)
  - Free Inquiry 1986 (Box-folder 5:59)
  - Freedom from Religion Foundation 1986-1988, n.d. (Box-folder 5:60)
  - Freedom Now for Lieutenant Howe Committee n.d. (Box-folder 5:61)
  - Freedom of Information Act 1986, n.d. (Box-folder 5:62)
  - Freethought n.d. (Box-folder 5:63)
  - The Freeze 1985, n.d. (Box-folder 5:64)
  - Freeze Voter 1984-1986 (Box-folder 5:65)
  - Frente Democratico Revolucionario n.d. (Box-folder 5:66)
  - Friend Shipment 1975-1977, n.d. (Box-folder 5:67)
  - Friends Committee on National Legislation 1960-1980 (Box-folder 5:68)
  - Friends of Bob Graham 1986 (Box-folder 5:69)
  - Friends of Micronesia n.d. (Box-folder 5:70)
  - Friends of the Filipino People n.d. (Box-folder 5:71)
  - Frontlash n.d. (Box-folder 6:1)
  - Fund for a Democratic Majority 1986 (Box-folder 6:2)
  - Fund for Freedom n.d. (Box-folder 6:3)
  - Fund for Freedom n.d. (Box-folder 6:3)
  - Fund for Open Information and Accountability, Inc. (FOIA, Inc.) n.d. (Box-folder 6:4)
  - Fund for Southern Communities 1985-1988 (Box-folder 6:5)
  - Funding Exchange 1979-1984 (Box-folder 6:6)
  - Georgetown University Students Against Registration and the Draft 1980 (Box-folder 6:7)
  - Gil Scott Heron n.d. (Box-folder 6:8)
  - Gist: a quick reference aid on United States foreign relations 1983 (Box-folder 6:9)
  - Glad Day Press n.d. (Box-folder 6:10)
  - Global Information Service: Charlottesville, Virginia n.d. (Box-folder 6:11)
  - Gold Star Parents for Amnesty n.d. (Box-folder 6:12)
  - Good Money n.d. (Box-folder 6:13)
  - The Grand Jury Project 1982, n.d. (Box-folder 6:14)
  - The Green Revolution: The School of Living and Healthcote Community n.d. (Box-folder 6:15)
  - Greenpeace n.d. (Box-folder 6:16)
  - Greensboro Justice Fund 1981-1984, n.d. (Box-folder 6:17)
  - The Guardian 1979-1984 (Box-folder 6:18)
  - Guatemala Human Rights Commission 1984, n.d. (Box-folder 6:19)
  - Guatemala News and Information Bureau 1983 (Box-folder 6:20)
  - The Guerrilla Theater: Charlottesville, Virginia: Compiled Scrapbook 1972, n.d. (Box-folder 6:21)
  - Gulf Boycott Coalition n.d. (Box-folder 6:22)
  - Haitian Refugee Center 1988 (Box-folder 6:23)
  - The Hammer and the Sickle 1980 (Box-folder 6:24)
  - Hammer and Tongs: The Socialist Party n.d. (Box-folder 6:25)
  - Hard Times Conference 1976 (Box-folder 6:26)
  - Harrisburg 8: Eqbal Ahmad 1971-1972, n.d. (Box-folder 6:27)
  - Hashomer Hazair: Zionists Against Imperialism n.d. (Box-folder 6:28)
  - Health Research Group n.d. (Box-folder 6:29)
  - Hear the Children: Boycott Campbell's Soup n.d. (Box-folder 6:30)